Su-won...
スウォン
本字幕由✿花語&花丸字幕組✿共同製作
ヨナ
Yona?
イル陛下はもう目を開けません
King Il will not wake again.
私が殺しました
I killed him.
Are you an illusion?
幻でしょうか
貴方は...
You're...
ヨナ姫がなくなられました
Princess Yona is dead.
I heard you had died on the cliffs
of the northern mountains.
貴方は北山の崖で亡くなったと聞いて
本当にヨナ姫なんですね
You really are Princess Yona.
お妃様がしていた様に眠るまで手を握っています
I'll hold your hand until you fall asleep, like the queen did.
ヨナの涙が零れたら誰かに見られないように拭ってあげます
If you cry, I'll wipe the tears away, so no one will see.
だから明日は笑って
So please smile tomorrow.
otome yo
O maiden!
akatsuki ni moeagare
Flare up in the dawning sun!
muchi de kayowaku mamorareru dake no
I want to tear off the guise of the ignorant
hime nugisutete watashi wa ikitai
Frail protected princess and live
mukashi yori sukoshi dake suki ni nareta
To conquer the color of the burning dawn
akatsuki no sora no iro nabikase
That I've recently started enjoying
rinzen to tsuyoku
With strength and commanding presence
kedakaku sora wo miagete
I strive to be someone I'm proud of
hokoreru jibun ni narou
And looking up idealistically to the sky
mamori aishi tsuranuku
To protect, to love, to stand my ground
keshite ubawasenai
I won't allow myself to lose anything again
kedakai hana no you ni
Like a noble flower
hitamuki na jounetsu de
With single-minded passion
zankoku na sadame sae
Even if faced with a cruel fate
kirihiraite miseru kara
I will push through
Episode 23:
Morning of Promise
What are you doing here?
何故此処に
ハクはどうしました
Where is Hak?
いや 愚問でした
No, that's a stupid question.
貴方が無事なのだ
You're safe.
それはきっと彼が今も貴方を命懸けで守り抜いてるからなのでしょう
I'm sure it's because he's still
risking his life to protect you.
阿波の領主 ヤンクムジが
I came here to investigate
because I'd heard Yan Kum-ji,
他国と違法の商売をしていると聞いて
the Lord of Awa, was conducting illegal business with another country.
偵察に来たのですが
Lord Su-won!
スウォン様
離して
Let go-
Quiet. Be still.
静かに じっとしていなさい
スウォン様
Lord Su-won...
お一人で歩かれては困ります
You can't walk off on your own.
ジュド将軍 ごめんなさい
General Ju-doh, I apologize.
新しい町はついわくわくしちゃって
I'm just so excited to be in a new city.
ついわくわくして
You're excited?
それって 女ですか
Is that why you're with a woman?
Huh?
やだなジュド将軍ってば
Please, General Ju-doh!
That's surprisingly crude of you.
意外と野暮なんですね
貴方がどこの女と遊ぼうんが勝手ですよ
What women you flirt with is your business!
しかしお忍びの偵察偵察中にすることですか
But in the middle of a secret reconnaissance mission isn't the time!
帰ってしろ 帰って
Do it when we get home!
General, not so loud.
将軍 声が大きいです
Calm down.
落ち着いて
分かりました分かりました
Fine, fine.
ちゃんとこの人とはお別れしますから
I'll send her away.
ところでヤンクムジは
By the way, where is Yan Kum-ji?
消息不明です
He's missing.
Last night, on his way to sell
slaves to the Kai Empire,
昨夜 人身売買の取引で戒帝国へ向かう途中
he was attacked by pirates.
海賊に襲撃されたとされ
What about the people Kum-ji was trying to sell?
それでクムジが売ろうとしていた人達は
全員 無事のようです
They all seem to be fine.
よかった
That's good.
人々に被害はなかったんですね
Then there were no casualties among the people.
人身売買の噂は聞いていましたが
I'd heard rumors of human trafficking, but I had trouble finding evidence.
なかなか証拠が掴めず苦労しました
海賊の皆さんには感謝しないと
I must thank the pirates.
Huh?
感謝
Thank them?
We will overlook this incident.
この件は 不問にしましょう
ヤンクムジの後任には誰を
Who will succeed Yan Kum-ji?
それは後程 都に帰ってから
I'll decide after we return to the capital.
もういいですか ジュド将軍
Is that all, General Ju-doh?
勝手にしろ
Do as you please!
怒りんぼだな
You're so hot-headed.
私を殺したいですか
Do you want to kill me?
Of course you do.
当然ですね
でも 今は死ぬわけにはいかないんです
But I cannot die yet.
私にはやるべきことがあるから
There's something I must do.
さよなら ヨナ
Farewell, Yona.
姫さん
Princess!
おい どうした 何が
Hey, what's wrong? What happened?
He's earlier than I expected.
意外に早かったな
日暮れまで帰られぬかと思いましたよ
I thought you wouldn't return until dusk.
やだな 意地悪言わないで下さいよ
Oh, please. Don't tease me.
貴方には遊んでる暇など欠片もないはず
In my view, you have
no time to play around!
何のために即位を急いだかお忘れか
Have you forgotten why you
rushed your coronation?
いいえ 忘れたことなど
No, I haven't forgotten.
But it's unusual for you to chase women.
しかし 陛下が女遊びなんて珍しいですよ
城内の女だって誰一人見向きもなさらないのに
You don't even look at the women in the castle.
そんなにいい女だったんですか
Was she that attractive?
そうですね
Well...
とても忘れがたい人です
I suppose... you could say she's unforgettable.
Anyway, we should hurry.
それより 急ぎましょう
次はどちらへ
Where to next?
地均しは済みました
I'm done making preparations.
戻ります
Let's return.
緋龍城へ
To Hiryuu Castle.
Ki-ja, wake up!
キジャ 起きて起きて
いつまで寝てるの
How long are you going to sleep?
は はい 頑張ります
Y-Yes! I'll do my best!
キジャ変な顔
Ki-ja, you look funny!
姫様 お元気ですね
Princess, you seem well.
もちろん 元気元気
Of course! I'm great!
Whoa, there.
元気元気
I'm great!
Yun...
ユン
what are you making?
何作ってるの
鮑粥
Abalone porridge.
皆酒ばっかじゃ胃に負担だからさ
Drinking nothing but alcohol will strain everyone's stomachs.
間にこれを挟もうと思って
I thought I'd slip this in.
美味しそう
It looks delicious!
よそうね
I'll serve it.
Huh?
Ah, hot!
ヨナ 大丈夫
Yona! Are you okay?
I-I'm fine.
平気平気
Time to eat, everyone!
皆御飯よ
飯？ こっちこっち
Food!
Yona, over here!
美味しい
It's delicious!
さすがユン 天才ね
You really are a genius, Yun.
よ ヨナちゃん 零してるよ
Y-Yona, you're spilling.
What are you doing, miss?
なにやってんだ嬢ちゃん
Wipe it up with this.
これで拭いて
Uh, Yona?
ヨナちゃん
Yona!
着替えなら 船長の部屋借りてください
If you're going to change,
use the captain's quarters.
ハク
Hak...
はい 見物料千銀
That'll be a thousand rin.
Huh?
今のは不可抗力だ
That was an act of God!
というか折角いい所だったのに
And it was just getting good.
Why did you st-
なんで止め...
Whap
どうしたんだい彼女
What's wrong with her?
Nothing.
別に
Huh.
立派な大刀だね
That's quite a blade.
そんなもの持ち歩いてたら町の人間が驚くよ
People will be shocked to see you walking around town with it.
Yeah. Until now, I've avoided carrying it in town.
これまで町じゃ持ち歩かないようにしてたんだけどな
I've been complacent lately.
近頃平和ボケしてたから
戒めだ
I need to be careful.
いいね
That's rich.
今朝まで戦場にいたくせに 平和ボケときたか
You were fighting until morning,
and you say you're complacent?
その見据えた視線の先にいる人物に興味があるね
I'm curious to know who you're staring at so intently.
Ah, either way...
それにしても
なんて悲しい殺気だ
What sorrowful bloodlust.
アオ
Ao...
私は好きですよ ヨナの髪
But I love your hair, Yona.
綺麗な赤 暁の空の色です
It's a beautiful red, like the sky at dawn.
外に出て いろんなことがあったなぁ
A lot has happened since I left.
そうっすね
It sure has.
You scared me.
びっくりした
どこにでもいるのね ハク
You're everywhere, Hak.
あんたのにる所にはね
Everywhere you are.
今朝は不覚にも目を離しまいましたが
This morning, I let you out of my sight.
一応専属護衛なんでうぜぇくらい隣にいるから
But because I'm your bodyguard, I'll stick annoyingly close to you.
If you need anything, call me.
なんかあったら呼んでくださいよ
Yeah.
ハク 私 ここを発つわ
Hak, I'm leaving.
Come with me.
一緒に来て
はいよ
You got it.
Huh?
皆 何してるの
What are you doing?
Oh, I, um...
わ 私はその...
ちょっと そういう話は俺等にも言ってよね
You should've told us!
Huh?
Don't "Huh?" me!
へじゃない
About you leaving!
出発の話
そういうことは皆がいる時に言わないと締まらないでしょう
You can't talk about that without all of us here.
そうです姫様
That's right, Princess.
我等四龍は貴方が命じれば地の果てまでも参ります
If you command, the four dragons will travel to the ends of the Earth.
Oh, you can leave now.
お前もう帰っていいぞ
What?!
なに
There are only two dragons here, anyway.
そもそも我等四龍って 二人しかいねぇし
Shut up!
う うるさい
Every time you "feel something over there,"
all I feel is annoyed.
Must you always try to pick fights with me?
Stop it-
Guys...
みんな
I'm leaving Awa tomorrow.
明日 阿波を発つ
Will you come with me?
一緒に付いて来てくれる
I will accompany you.
お供します
Yes.
めんどくさ
What a pain.
Huh?!
You're cute. Marry me.
お兄さん可愛い 結婚して
ばば 結婚 結婚はもう...
Marry you? I can't do that!
How cute. He's half-asleep.
可愛い 暈けてる
素敵な音色
What a beautiful sound.
Would you like to try?
引いてみる
Screech
海賊の方が向いてるみたいんだね
You make a better pirate than a musician.
琴と舞なら少しは出来るわ
I can play the harp and dance a little.
琴と舞ね
Play the harp and dance, huh?
まだ笑うのジェハ
You're still laughing at me, Jae-ha?
No, I was just thinking you really are a girl.
いや 君は女の子なんだと思ってんさ
君はこんなにも小さくて危なっかしくて力が無くて面倒だ
You're a small, unsteady,
and powerless pain in the butt.
You're insulting me?
悪口？
更に僕をこんなところまで探しに来て
You also came all the way here to look for me.
迷惑極まりない
You're an enormous nuisance.
安心して
Don't worry!
もうジェハを無理に連れて行ったりしないから
I won't push you to come with me anymore.
それじゃ
Goodbye.
I don't understand you, Jae-ha.
ジェハってよく分からない
至って素直な人間だよ僕は
I'm a very straightforward guy.
I like to spend the night of a party with a cute girl.
宴の夜は可愛い女の子と居たいからね
止めだやめだジェハ
That's enough, Jae-ha.
その曲は眠くなるわ
That song makes me sleepy.
Why don't you sleep, then?
だったら寝れば
Sixth After-Party (laugh)
町の連中はほとんど寝てるよ
Most of the townsfolk are asleep.
寝るだと 俺はまだ飲み足りん
Me either!
俺もだ
子守唄
Lullaby...
Snore
Stop that, you idiot! You'll put us to sleep!
止せアホ 寝ちまうだろう
So why not sleep?
だから寝れば
I won't sleep, damn it!
クソ寝ないぞ
I'm not... going to sleep.
寝て堪るかよ
酔っ払いの面倒は見ないよ マヤ
I don't take care of drunks, Maya.
寝たら 夢から覚めちまう
If we go to sleep, the dream will end.
Dream?
夢
Of being a pirate.
海賊さ
今夜が俺等 海賊の最後の夜だ
This is our last night as pirates.
That's why...
だから
Idiots.
バカだな
海賊でなくなっても 皆阿波で漁師をやるんだろう
Even if you're not pirates anymore,
you'll keep fishing in Awa, won't you?
だったら これまでと何も変わりは...
That hardly changes anythi-
But you're leaving!
お前は行っちまうだろう
You're leaving Awa with that girl and her friends!
嬢ちゃん達と阿波から出て行っちまうんだろう
子守唄
Lullaby...
Snore
Jae-ha... I'll kill you.
ジェハ 殺したい
Droopy Eyes
鬱陶しいな
How annoying.
I really do love you guys.
本当 僕は君達が...大好きだよ
May I join you, my beauty?
ご一緒しても 美しい人
うせぇな ひょろひょろ小僧
Go away, you lanky brat.
いつ聞いても痺れるね 船長の毒舌
Your vitriol still sends shivers up my spine.
船長は僕の理想の女性なんだよ
You're my ideal woman, Captain.
僕が五十年早く生まれていれば...
If only I were fifty years older-
クムジに受けた矢傷はここかい
Is this where Kum-ji shot you?
Did the "fifty years" thing offend you?
五十年が気に障りました
You're always running off to see other women.
他所の女の所へ行く分際でよく言うよ
おや 焼いてくれるんだ
Oh, so you're jealous.
あの娘が何者か分かってんのかい
Do you understand who she is?
まっ なんとなくね
Well, more or less.
厳しいよ あの子に付いていくのは
Following her won't be easy.
龍の定めって奴かい
Is this the dragon's destiny?
知らないよ
I don't know.
ただ どうもね 目の届く所にいてくれないと落ち着かない
But it seems I just can't stand it
when she's out of my sight.
そう 何の力もないくせに
Indeed, even though she's powerless.
泣きながら進んでいく背中が頼りなくて
She's unreliable, crying as she moves forward.
なのに その輝きに飲み込まれそうで
But her brilliance consumes me.
あの矢を射る姿はそそられたな
The way she shot that arrow
roused something inside me.
射られたクムジがちょっと羨ましかった
I was sort of jealous she shot Kum-ji instead of me.
仲良くくたばりゃよかったんだ
You should have died with him.
お前みたいな変態はとっとと行っちまいな
Get out of here already, you pervert!
二度と帰ってくるんじゃないよ
Don't come back.
You're no fun.
つれないな
お前の家はいつだってここにあるよ くらい 言ってくれないの
You won't even tell me
I'll always have a home here?
言ってほしけりゃ
If that's what you want,
私を落とせる口説き文句の一つでもひっさげて来な ハナタレ小僧
you'll need to do a better job wooing me,
you snot-nosed brat.
なんだいお前は 空から降ってきて
Who are you? You fell out of the sky.
なんでもするから置いてくれだって
If I let you stay, you'll do anything?
バカなハナタレだね
You're a foolish brat.
女の口説き方を知らないのかい
Don't you know how to woo a woman?
You're finally leaving, Yona?
ついに行っちまうのか ヨナちゃん
Come back soon, kid!
坊主 また来いよ
絶対来いよ 死んでも来いよ
Promise you'll come back, even if it kills you!
That hurts!
痛いよ
どうしたのですか
What's wrong?
ジェハがいないの
Jae-ha's missing.
お礼とか言いたいこといっぱいあったのに
I wanted to talk to him and thank him.
Who cares about that droopy-eyed-
どうでもいいだろう あんなたれ目
よくない
I care!
I can't leave like this.
このままお別れなんて
ジェハね
Jae-ha, huh?
またいつかここに来れば会えるさ
If you ever come back, you'll see him.
はい
All right.
船がいる時は私に言いな
Let me know if you need a boat.
いつでも用意してやるよ
I'll keep one ready for you.
ありがとう
Thank you.
顔の腫れ まだ引いてないね
Your face is still swollen.
平気よ
I'm fine.
ひょろひょろ娘が逞しくなったじゃないか
You're not the frail little girl you used to be.
ひょろひょろ娘
Frail little girl?
You can't even clean, wash clothes, or cook properly.
掃除洗濯料理どれもまともに出来やしないくせに
女の嗜みだ
That's part of being a woman.
早く覚えな
You should learn soon.
無鉄砲だけが取り柄なんて 嫁の貰い手がないからね
No one wants to marry a girl
who's merely reckless.
余計なお世話
That's none of your business!
問題ないでしょう
It's not a problem.
山で芝刈りしてる間に河出洗濯をしてくれる旦那見つければ
Just find a husband to wash your clothes while you cut grasses in the mountains.
ハクは黙ってて
You be quiet, Hak!
嬢ちゃん 阿波の料理は魚さえ焼けりゃ大丈夫だから
Miss, in Awa, you only need to be able to cook fish.
それと刺身な
That or serve it raw.
おお 嫁に行くとこなかったら俺んとこ来な
If you can't find a husband, come marry me!
I'm not marrying you!
行きません
You're all so rude.
もうみんな失礼だから
出発
I'm leaving!
お待ち
Wait.
持って行きな
Take this.
Huh?
Oh, senjuso! That'll help.
おぉ 千樹草 助かる
This is too much.
こんなに沢山
Don't catch a cold.
風邪 引くんじゃないよ
なんか船長母ちゃんみたいんだな
The captain sort of sounds like a mom.
それではお世話になりました
Thank you for everything.
Take care!
元気でよ
Come see us again!
まだ遊びに来いよ
待ってるぞ坊主
I'll be waiting for you, kid!
Goodbye!
さよなら
ヨナ
Yona?
They're gone.
行っちまったな
さて 漁師の仕事だ
Well, time to fish!
The girl wasn't one of the pirates?
あの娘は海賊の一味ではなかったのか
どうりで海賊にしちゃ可愛い
I knew she was too cute to be one.
Oh? She may look cute, but she's stronger than your average soldier.
あら 外見は可愛いけど あの子は並の兵士より強いのよ
なんたってあのクムジを討ったんだもの
After all, she shot Kum-ji.
Huh? That girl shot Kum-ji?
あの娘さんがクムジを
It was so cool!
もう超格好よかったんだから
That girl did, huh?
あの子がね
What are you talking about?
何の話してるんだい
ヨナ もう泣き止んで
Yona, stop crying.
そなたも泣いておるぞユン
You're crying too, Yun.
一番泣いてんのはてめぇだ白蛇
You're crying more than anyone, White Snake.
I didn't get to say goodbye to Jae-ha.
結局 ジェハにはお別れ出来なかった
ジェハ 彼は仲間になったのではないのですか
Jae-ha? I thought he joined us.
Huh?
Jae-ha!
ジェハ
Hey.
どうして
Why?
緑龍 ずっと近くにいた
The Green Dragon was always nearby.
いや ちょっと暇になったんで
I didn't have anything else to do,
ヨナちゃんと旅をするのも悪くないかなって思ったんだけど
so I thought traveling with you
might not be so bad.
But seeing you in tears while looking for me was unbearably exciting, so here I am.
どうも 泣きそうになりながら僕を探す君を見ていたら
堪らなく興奮しちゃって ついね
声をかける機会を逃してしまったのさ
I missed my chance to reveal myself.
I see you're still a pervert.
相変わらず変態だな
He reminds me of you, Thunder Beast.
雷獣と同じ匂いを感じるよ
でも 四龍の掟に縛られるの嫌だって あんなに
But you said you didn't want to be bound by the laws of the four dragons.
四龍なんて関係ないよ
This isn't about the four dragons.
今までもこれからも
I'll continue to pursue the path I choose for myself, as I always have.
自分で選び進んだ道を行くだけ
何も僕の美学に反してはいない
That's still in accordance with my aesthetic.
今はただ君をほって置けなくてね
I just can't leave you now.
連れてって ヨナ
Take me with you, Yona.
調子のいいことぬかしてんじゃねぇよ
Don't get ahead of yourself.
That's right.
そうだよ
ヨナとの二人旅じゃないんだから
You aren't just traveling with Yona.
俺等にも挨拶して貰わないと
You'd better acknowledge us as well.
その通り
He's right.
我等は礼節を重んじる者
We value etiquette...
緑龍
Green Dragon.
それは失礼
Please excuse me.
では改めて
Allow me to reintroduce myself.
My name is Jae-ha.
僕の名はジェハ
右足に龍を宿す美しき化け物だよ
I'm a beautiful monster with a dragon in my right leg.
以後よろしく
I look forward to traveling with you.
modoranai hibi ni namida koboshite
Crying tears for the days that won't return
miageta sora ga akaku akaku moeru
You look up to the sky, and it's burning bright red
jibun no tsuyosa yowasa kizuketa no nara ima
Now that you know your own strength and weakness
kimi yo osoreruna kokoro omomuku mama
You should have no fear and go where your heart takes you
kaze wo kirisusumu sono tabiji wo
Cleaving through the wind, your path is lit
akatsuki ga terasu
By the dawn
(tsudoe takeki kaina)
(Gather, fierce arm)
(senri no hitomi)
(All-seeing eyes)
sora wo kakeyuku ashi
Feet that dash through the sky
(kuon no tate)
(Shield of eternity)
inishie no chikai ima hatashite
Fulfill the ancient vows
yoru yo akete yuke
O night, break into dawn
Next Time
I'm sorry, Hak.
ごめんね ハク
雨が上がったら 私はまた剣をとるわ
Once the rain stops, I'm taking up a sword again.
次回 暁のヨナ 第二十四話
Next time, Akatsuki no Yona, episode 24:
Episode 24:
From Now On
これから
From Now On.